futurestud.io 2019-03-27

# Privacy Policy

Last updated: April 12, 2018

## Thank You for Using Future Studio!

As long we don’t need your personal data (e.g. your name, address or e-mail-address) for providing our services all information you share with **Future Studio** is optional.

We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this privacy policy.

All references in this terms (e.g. “website”, “services”) are bound to the domain “futurestud.io”; “we”, “us”, “our” refer to **Future Studio** as a company.

## Cookies

Cookies are files with a small amount of data for record keeping purposes. We delete most of them automatically after your visit _(session cookies)_. We use cookies to collect information in order to improve our services for you (e.g. _remember me_ -functionality on login).

You may set up your computer to reject cookies although, in that case, you may not be able to use certain features on our Website.

## Matomo

Whenever you visit our services we may collect information that your browser sends. This information may include your computer’s IP-address, browser type, browser version, the pages you visit inside our domain, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages and other statistics. To monitor and analyze this type of information we are using Matomo in a self hosted environment.

You don't have to share this information with us if you don't want to. Enable _Do Not Track_ if you don't want to share this information with us.

_Do Not Track_ is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

## MailChimp

We use MailChimp to manage our newsletters and mailing lists. Sending Mails via MailChimp give us the ability to analyze how many subscribers opened our mails or clicked a link inside our mails. You are bound by their Privacy Policies if you become part of one of our mailing lists.

## YouTube

Our website is using a _YouTube-Plugin by Google Inc._ , to embed videos from our channel directly inside our blogposts.

Content with video embeds are marked with a __and can be found via search or tutorial overview pages.

By accessing a website (not limited to futurestud.io) with a youtube-embed you will send a _referrer header_ to YouTube.

That means by accessing one of our tutorials that contains a video-embed - YouTube can log and analyze that you were on our domain even if you don't watching it.

You are bound by the Privacy Policies of Google Inc. if you watch our videos.

## Disqus

As part of our community work we want to give you the possibility to discuss and comment our contents. For this purpose we are using _Disqus_. Disqus is a third party service you have to register for, if you want to leave a comment. You are bound by their Terms of Usage and Privacy Policies if you use our comment functionality.

Notice that we moderate our comment sections and try our best to answer your questions and feedback as quickly as possible. We are not responsible for any comments made by other users than [futurestudio](https://disqus.com/by/futurestudio/)

## Braintree

We don't retain any financial information - to manage all payment processing with Future Studio we use the payment service provider _Braintree by PayPal Inc._. By buying any products on our website you share your financial information with Braintree and are bound to their Terms of Usage and Privacy Policies. 

## Social Media

We use several social media plugin-buttons to give you the possibility to share our content with your friends, coworkers or followers. By clicking on one of our social media buttons you will send a _referrer header_ to the respective platform. The referrer header contains information about your browser (e.g. your IP-addess, the url of the page you want to share). Clicking on a social media button will open a pop-up window which is loading the user interface of the selected social media platform.

Social Media platforms we support are **Twitter** , **Google+** and **Facebook**. These platforms will not share any informations from your profile with us (e.g. your contacts, the content of your message). 

## How we use Your Data

While using our services, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally information that can be used to contact or identify you. Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to, your email address, full name or residence.

We collect this information for the purpose of providing our services, identifying and communicating with you, responding to your requests/inquiries or servicing you products you purchased before. 

We also use your data to analyze and improve our services. But we never use your personal data directly. Your data is anonymized and is a statistic part of the data of all our users and visitors.

If you have purchased one of our products we have to keep a proof your financial transactions due to legal requirements. 

## Contact

If you have any questions about these Policies, please contact us.

Get in touch via:

  * Telephone: [+49 162 / 61 60 920](tel:+1626160920)   

  * E-Mail: [info@futurestud.io](mailto:info@futurestud.io)
